# SCOTT GILBERT

802.598.9250 | scottvtgilbert@gmail.com

## WEB DEVELOPER

Methodical problem solver seeking to apply experience with establishing and improving systems and workflows to building web based solutions. Proven track record of success using a systematic, dedicated and positive approach to work that results in satisfied clients and coworkers. Looking to unite these skills with several years of web development education and project based experience to contribute to web development projects large and small.

## **EDUCATION**

•	Software Development Bootcamp - Upright Education	2022
•	Javascript After Hours - Burlington Code Academy	2021
•	Accounting Certificate - Champlain College	2012
•	Bachelor of Science - Applied Mathematics   University of Vermont	2009

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

•	JavaScript	•	React	•	Node.js	•	Express.js	•	Next.js	•	Bootstrap
•	HTML/CSS	•	Sass	•	MySQL	•	MongoDB	•	Git/Github	•	Wordpress

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

Bear Cobble HQ | bearcobble.com / bearcobble.herokupapp.com (v2 beta)| JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, Smartrek Monitoring Systems

- Information systems dashboard for a large-scale sugaring operation;
- Real-time display of equipment monitoring sensors, digital maps, real time weather sensors, weather forecasts, woods infrastructure repair and issue tracking lists, equipment performance logs.

### CreekVT | creekvt.com | JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, PHP, MySQL, Wordpress, Express.js, Heroku, Amazon AWS

 A collection of resources for Vermont whitewater kayakers; real time flow information, river level reporting system and database, remote cameras for river level monitoring, recent rainfall data, real time weather radar, variety of river guides, maps and other information.

## Halls & Hawk Lakes Property Owners Association | hallshawklakes.ca | JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, PHP, MySQL, Wordpress

• A property owner's association website for a Canadian Lakes Association focused on dissemination of information; membership management system, volunteer signup system, woocommerce store, newsletter management system. Migrated from a previous Wordpress site and host in 2020 with additional features added through 2022.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Sap Mappers LLC | Owner/Operator - May 2018 - Present

- Performed mapping and data collection utilizing GPS / GIS software, primarily for large scale sugaring operations.
- Created infrastructure network identification and labeling systems
- Produced digital, web-based, and printed maps, resulting in improved woods crew productivity and woods management practices for clients.
- Performed non-sugaring related GIS and GPS work for a variety of additional clients.

#### Bear Cobble Sugar Works | Factotum - October 2018 - Present

- Established information management systems, including construction of a web-based dashboard for equipment sensor output, weather information, maps and infrastructure repair tracking table.
- Produced maps and maintained infrastructure data via GIS software.
- Oversaw Sugarhouse Certification via VMSMA passing as the first operation to require no corrective actions.
- Performed all aspects of bulk maple syrup production in a 32,000 tap sugarwoods.
- Quality of work performed resulted in the operation's 3 most successful years of production.

### Runamok Maple | Cost Analyst / Production and Inventory Manager January 2015 - January 2018

- Scheduled and oversaw production of retail products.
- Managed inventory of finished goods and raw materials.
- Established systems for batch tracking, production flow and scheduling, and order management.
- Performed cost analysis of production, including quoting private label work.
- Assisted the accounting department with costing of production, inventory valuation and special projects.